So, you're saying you can't tell us, no matter what?
You see, there's this alien—
Scieszka, keep quiet.
Still, you couldn't have wound up in the power distribution station
just because you'd
lost your way, right?
What exactly were you
doing in there?
Sergeant...
What are you
going to do now?
Um, Lieutenant Ross...
There's something going on
within the military.
Something very dangerous.
Thanks.
Winry-san,
what do we do now?
I'm going back to
Resembool for now.
I'd like to talk to Ed and Al,
but I don't know where they are.
Then what should I do?
What are you talking about? You're coming with me!
But what about
my books at home?
Leave them there.
Hey...
I can take this off now, right?
Be my guest.
Ah, that's better.
The Crimson...
Well, well, if it isn't the Flame Major—make that Colonel.
Is something the matter?
Archer!
What is the meaning of this?!
Do you have some issue with the Crimson Alchemist, Lt. Colonel Zolf J. Kimbly?
Lt. Colonel?!
The Lt. Colonel was imprisoned on false charges,
and just before he was subjected to unlawful human experimentation at the 5th Laboratory,
he made a successful escape.
Thanks to the Lt. Colonel's testimony, the facts about the 5th Laboratory are coming to light.
False charges?!
That's outrageous!
Do not forget that
for this operation,
the Führer has granted me
the rank of colonel.
By the way, who was
that telephone call from?
Oh...
Do you know of
a town called Liore?
What's that?
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
So, you're the one...
Yeah. I killed Greed.
Brother! What good
does it do to say that now?
Martel, I don't know
what you were thinking,
but to me, you and Greed were both criminals who kidnapped my brother.
What's more,
he also killed Dante-san.
Martel-san!
Look out!
A snake?
You're not who I'm after.
Greed-san chose death
rather than being sealed up again.
He was, more than anything,
a proud man.
And so, I believe he wanted to be defeated by you.
The ones who I detest are
the military who killed my friends,
and those two
who dress all in black,
as well as the man
who betrayed my friends.
Kimbly!
Why don't you eat it?
They're nutritious.
Oh, my. If I did that, it would be cannibalism, wouldn't it?
We're getting close to Liore, huh?
Yeah.
I wonder how Rose-san is doing.
Who's that?
Don't pretend you've forgotten.
Brother, you've been a little worried about her, right?
Hey, Martel, how soon
before we get to Ishbal?
We're here.
We've long since entered Ishbal.
This is Ishbal?
There's nothing here,
huh, Brother?
We need some way
to find Scar, but this...
What exactly are you
looking for, anyway?
A Philosopher's Stone.
There was a man who said
they had created a Philosopher's Stone before Ishbal was destroyed.
That can't be true.
They offered no resistance
and were killed before they
had a chance to take up arms.
No way they offered
no resistance!
The military and Ishbal had
a long and tense military relationship.
Then an incident where a soldier mistakenly shot a civilian took place,
and the Ishbalans rose up.
So that's really
how it was presented...
I didn't know.
I was in that laboratory for a little over fourteen years.
Since just after the civil war in Ishbal broke out?
Thanks to being turned into a Chimera,
I may look young,
but I'm your fairly older sister.
You mean aunt—
Sorry.
We were a special operations unit.
We weren't told
what our destination was
or what the details of our mission were
until the last minute.
That's the way
they usually did it.
What's going on?!
We're in dire straits!
What's going on?
I don't know! But people are being killed!
The mission we had been given
was to infiltrate the Ishbalan city
and conduct large-scale subversive activities.
In any case, let's get someplace safe!
It was under the pretext of preventing them
from carrying out acts of terrorism
that they were planning to commit against Central.
And you're saying that's what
brought about the Ishbalan uprising?
What reason would the military have for starting a war with Ishbal?!
I don't know
what the reason was.
There, you see?!
But I do have proof.
I don't get it.
Just listen to me.
Right after the Ishbalan
Civil War started,
we were placed in custody.
Anyone who resisted...
Dammit!
What's going on here?!
We were following military orders!
Those who survived were
taken to the 5th Laboratory.
Dolcetto!
Martel!
What is this?
They made you a Chimera.
The military tried to
completely silence us. Why?
Because you knew a secret that
absolutely could not be leaked out—
the truth about
the start of the war.
But why?
Why would the military
provoke Ishbal?!
Someone's there?
What?
It's a lead!
You're not getting away!
Now then, let's have you tell me
what you're doing here.
Th-This area is
off-limits to civilians.
We're here to check on the security of the old Ishbalan cities.
Then you could've just shown yourselves instead of sneaking around, right?
Yeah. He may not look it,
but my brother is a State Alchemist.
What are you guys, moles?
Brother, could those men be...
Yo...
You guys...
Then the Colonel is here too?
Well aren't you a familiar face?
Yeah, yeah, same old shrimp who's so small
you'd lose sight of him
among the grains of san—
Who are you calling that?!
I hear you've been raising hell
all over the place.
The Southern Command Center,
as well as the Ishbalan escort train.
Anyhow, you're under
my command from now on.
Just a moment, please!
You're lucky that Havoc caught you when they were out scouting.
But we're supposed to have permission to continue our journey independently.
However, once called up,
I become a dog of the military.
Brother...
They've come all the way out to this
remote region in a military transport train.
Don't tell me there's a war.
We're just quelling
a somewhat seditious area.
Our target is a town about two
kilometers south-southeast of here.
You're pretty heavily armed, considering.
Are we?
Shall I tell you why you're here?
It's Scar, right?
We were just looking
for him ourselves.
What are your reasons
for pursuing Scar?
If we don't put him down,
he's going to make a lot of trouble.
Oh, Alphonse-kun,
you don't have to force yourself to pretend you're eating.
Y-Yes, you're right.
I'll kill that woman!
What's that?
The latest photographs
from our surveillance balloon.
Is that...
It couldn't be...
A transmutation circle
made from the whole city?
Who would do such a thing?
I won!
Scar.
So it is him?
Edward-kun, do you know what his objective is?
No. So, what town is this?
The town is named Liore.
Last year, its tyrannical priest retired,
and peace has just barely returned with the stationing of troops there.
Sergeant Fuery...
Sir?
He knows.
Liore, you say?
An armed uprising in Liore?
This shouldn't be happening!
We put down that bogus priest and brought peace to the city!
No.
After that, the people divided into
a priest faction and a citizen's faction,
and there has been
terrible confusion.
When the military went in
to gather a situation report,
both factions stood against them.
Why didn't you
tell me about this?!
I was involved in this
from the start!
I heard the report from Hughes, but I kept it back.
Why?!
Because it was too much for you to handle.
Don't Ed-kun and Al-kun know about Brigadier General Hughes?
Apparently not.
If he tells them now, they'd probably just dash back to Central, and all.
He is an important military asset,
and everything.
Edward-kun and his brother are in a dangerous position right now.
He probably wants to have them in a place where he can keep his eye on them.
Um, is my brother here?
You will give me first priority when reporting.
And if you will observe my earlier conditions,
I will grant you permission.
Ed! What are you doing here?!
At his insistence,
I am having him
reconnoiter the town of Liore.
You're sending one of our precious State Alchemists out to sightsee?
Which is exactly why no matter what happens,
he will come back to us alive.
Besides,
he knows more about Liore than anyone else does.
Please put your mind at ease.
He said he would
leave his brother here.
He's not about to leave his dear brother here and disappear by himself on us, right?
Why didn't you tell me?!
If I had, would you have given me permission?
You've learned about Liore, and now you're confused.
That's why I'm going to
cool my head now.
Phew, it was hot in there.
Be careful. The way the military sees it, you're a wanted person.
Brother, are you serious about this? You're going to Liore alone?
Leaving you behind
was the bargaining point.
Archer doesn't trust us at all.
I wonder if that transmutation circle is for a Philosopher's Stone.
If it is, I'm going to destroy it.
Martel, behave yourself.
I know. I held myself back in front of
that Archer guy earlier, didn't I?
I'm going to kill those guys in black and Kimbly first.
Taking my revenge against
the military comes after that.
I'm not going to let you
do that, you know.
Brother, be really careful, okay?
Yeah.
M-Major...
You're here?
Colonel Archer said to
leave your silver watch here.
Oh yeah. I guess it would be trouble if someone found out my position.
Edward Elric,
why did you come here?
Fate, maybe?
That's not like you.
I doubt you two
even believe in fate.
A new silver watch has arrived.
Give this one the transmutation amplification treatment as well.
Is that right?
You were driven out of the city because of that priest, huh?
That Cornello guy was
positively awful, all right.
By the way, I get the feeling that
I've seen your face around somewhere.
Really?
Must be one of those
common faces.
It's the Holy Mother!
You're in luck!
Huh?
It's the Holy Mother.
Rose?
Please go back inside!
The Colonel said that under no circumstances was anyone to see you!
Because I'm officially deceased?
At least allow me to do as I like
in the evening.
But...
You sure are pesky.
No!
Kimbly!
Hey there.
To think that we would be
seeing the boy here again...
What should we do, Gluttony?
Pride told us, right?
The Ishbal...
um...
Kill anyone who knows the truth about Ishbal.
That's too bad.
I smell it. I smell it!
The smell of the Ishbalan beast!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 40: "The Scar"
Some people say that the scars
on your body disappear in time.
But there are some scars that you can't get rid of.